

# MAGESH V G

Senior Software Developer

## CONTACT \_\_\_\_\_

vgmagesh5@gmail.com

+91-9566824544

LinkedIn/Magesh

Chennai, TN, India.

# SKILLS \_\_\_\_\_

- ✓ HTML 5, CSS 3
- ✓ Javascript (JS)
- ✓ Typescript
- ✓ Angular
- ✓ React JS
- ✓ Java
- ✓ AWS Lambda
- ✓ MySQL
- ✓ Node JS
- ✓ Rest API

#### CERTIFICATION \_\_\_

✓ AWS Solutions

Architect - Associate

#### EDUCATION \_\_\_\_

B.TECH (IT) | 2011 - 2015

MPNMJ Engineering College,

Erode, Tamil Nadu, INDIA.

### HOBBIES

- Badminton Player
- Part time online Front-end trainer

## PROFILE SUMMARY

An enthusiastic and self-motivated Software Developer with an extensive experience of 7 years in designing, developing large scale distributed systems. Seeking to leverage full stack knowledge on developing interactive and user-centered applications. Constant drive for self-development and learning new technologies.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## ACCENTURE SOLUTIONS PRIVATE LIMITED

Software Prod and Platform Engineer Specialist | 2021 – \*Present.

#### FIDELITY INVESTMENTS

- CHENNAI, INDIA

- HYDERABAD, INDIA

Senior Software Engineer | 2019 – 2021.

## NEXT SPHERE TECHNOLOGIES PVT LTD

- CHENNAI, INDIA

Software Engineer | 2015 – 2019.

#### HANDS-ON

- Expertise in **HTML**, **CSS**, **Javascript**, **Typescript**, **Angular**, **React** Framework.
- Structured and designed reusable user interface **components** using Angular and React for the customer facing single page web application.
- Implemented authentication and authorization in frontend by consuming **Rest APIs** and with the help of singleton services.
- Responsible for API design and development of RESTful services by following enterprise standards with TDD.
- LED team of three to convert legacy spring application to AWS Lambda functions and Mentored peers on it.
- Cloud services: AWS EC2, AWS S3, AWS SQS, AWS RDS.
- Extensive knowledge on microservice architecture and cloud configured distributed systems. Used Kafka and Apache Camel as communication tools
- Self-taught knowledge on Nodejs, ExpressJS, MongoDB, GraphQL.
- Followed agile process and helped to prioritize and scope features to ensure that business needs were met at earliest.
- Used JIRA and confluence for ticket management and business requirements respectively
- Involved in peers code reviews, aided in bugfixes, guided in code quality and feature enhancements.
- Followed continuous integration and continuous development (CI/CD) through GIT based repository pull request and Jenkins jobs.
- ORM Tools: Spring Hibernate, JPA
- Build tools : **NPM**, maven
- Development Tools: VS code, IntelliJ, eclipse, and sequel pro.

## LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY \_\_\_\_\_

English